Finding Aid to Framed Items from the Collections of The Bancroft Library
The Bancroft Library
- Collections of Framed Items
  - Portraits of Californians: by Leola Hall Coggins, ca. 1900-ca. 1920?; Coggins, Leola Hall; BANC PIC 1946.012--FR and BANC PIC 1905.17134:226-:232--PIC; 14 paintings and drawings: some oil; various sizes
    - [August Vollmer], [19--]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1946.012:7-C; 1 painting on canvas mounted on gypsum board: oil; 52.7 x 43 cm. Painted signature (LL): Leola Hall Coggins.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Vollmer, August, -- 1876-1955 -- Portraits
  - Partington collection of paintings and relief sculpture, ca. 1879-ca. 1920; BANC PIC 1957.013--FR; 7 paintings on canvas and 1 relief sculpture: chiefly oil, 1 wood; 40 x 60 in. and smaller
    - [Portrait of a boy (possibly John Allen Partington I)], Sep 1879; Partington, John Herbert Evelyn; BANC PIC 1957.013:1--FR; 1 painting on board: oil; visible image 39.8 x 28.9 cm. Painted signature (LR): Partington / Sep. 1879
      Bust length oil sketch of young boy, possibly the youngest son of the artist.
    - [Ships in Bay, View of Angel Island (?)], [ca. 1879-ca. 1920]; Partington, John Herbert Evelyn; BANC PIC 1957.013:2--FR; 1 painting: oil; 25.2 x 41 cm.
      View of (San Francisco?) bay with two moored sailboats and a distant ferryboat. (Angel?) Island in distance.
      Oil paintings; San Francisco Bay (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Seascapes; Sailboats -- Pictorial works
    - [Study of Velásquez's Las Meninas], [ca. 1879-ca. 1920]; Albright, Gertrude P.; BANC PIC 1957.013:3--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 38.5 x 28 cm.
    - [Relief portrait (unfinished)], [ca. 1879-ca. 1920]; Albright, Gertrude P.; BANC PIC 1957.013:4--FR; 1 carving on wood panel; visible image 29.4 x 26.5 cm.
      Portrait head.
      Portraits; Sculpture -- relief
    - [Miss Blanche Partington], 1891; Partington, John Herbert Evelyn; BANC PIC 1957.013:5--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 126 x 101 cm. Painted signature and date (LL): J. H. E. Partington / 1891.
      Three-quarter length portrait of a woman (Partington, Blanche, d. 1951) standing near a piano holding a piece of sheet music by composer Franz Liszt.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Partington, Blanche, -- d. 1951 -- Portraits
    - [Kate Partington], [ca. 1879-ca. 1900]; Partington, John Herbert Evelyn; BANC PIC 1957.013:6--FR; 1 painting: oil; 91.5 x 71.5 cm. Painted signature (LL): J. H. E. Partington.
      Three-quarter length seated portrait of a woman (Partington, Kate, d. 1908) holding fan with peacock feathers.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Partington, Kate -- Portraits
    - [Edward Partington: My Beloved Brother], [ca. 1879-ca. 1920]; Albright, Gertrude P.; BANC PIC 1957.013:8--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 72.3 x 59.7 cm. Title and attribution from inventory. French manufacturers stamp (verso of canvas) from R. Foinet fils & Le Febvre.
      Half length portrait of man smoking a cigratte.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Partington, Edward -- Portraits
  - Items from: Mexia Collection: family portraits, Mexico & South American views., ca. 1860-ca. 1845; BANC PIC 1934.003-.004--PIC
    - [General Jose Antonio Mexia (1790-1839)], Unknown; BANC PIC 1934.003:01--FR; 1 painting: oil; 84 x 68 cm.
      Half-length portrait of man in military uniform wearing fur-lined green cape, pointing to soldiers in the distance. Born in Cuba, Jose Antonio Mexia came to Mexico in 1823, later became a General, led an expedition against Tampico in November 1835, and was eventually captured and shot by Santa Anna's forces in 1839.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Mexia family -- Pictorial works
    - [General Jose Antonio Mexia (1790-1839)], 1828; Serrano, Antonio; BANC PIC 1934.003:02--FR; 1 painting on canvas mounted on panel: oil; visible image 23.7 x 18.6 cm. Painted signature (LR): Ant.o Serrano / pinto. 1828. Handwritten (panel verso): Este es el retrato del Gene / ral Mexia [this is a picture of General Mexia].
      Half-length portrait of man in Military uniform.
    - [Portrait of Enrique Guillermo Antonio Mexia], [ca. 1860]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1934.003:05--FR; 1 painting: oil; 43.2 x 36 cm. Manufacturer's stamp (verso).
      Half length, oval portrait of bearded man in dress military uniform holding a saber and wearing a medal. Enrique Guillermo Antonio Mexia (1829-1896) fought in the war against the United States, on the liberal side in the War of the Reform 1857-1860, against the French invasion under Maximilian, and for Benito Juarez, as well as occupying himself with business and politics in his later years. Son of Jose Antonio Mexia and father of Inez Mexia.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Mexia family -- Pictorial works; Soldiers
    - [Portrait of Charlotte Walker Mexia], [1855]; Unknown (Payne?); BANC PIC 1934.003:18--FR; 1 painting: oil; 25.7 x 20.3 cm.
    - [Portrait of a "General of Rurales" on horseback], [189-?]; Silva, [J?]; Pellandini, Claudio; BANC PIC 1934.004:01--FR; 1 photograph mounted on wood panel with beveled edge: handcolored; visible image 9.7 x 13.7 cm. Painted signature (LR): Silva. Label (on verso) from El Antiguo Correo by photographer Claudio Pellandini, Mexico. Handwritten (label on verso): Portrait of a general of Rurales.
      Full length portrait of man on horseback wearing pseudo-military costume and wide brimmed hat.
    - [Man on horseback holding a rifle], [189-?]; Silva, [J?]; Pellandini, Claudio; BANC PIC 1934.004:02--FR; 1 photograph mounted on wood panel with beveled edge: handcolored; 9.3 x 5.8 cm. Painted signature (LR): [J?] Silva. Same signature and structure as BANC PIC 1934.004:1--FR; could also be product of El Antiguo Correo by photographer Claudio Pellandini, Mexico.
      Full length portrait of man on horseback.
    - [Ivory relief of two women], [18--?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1934.004:03--FR; 1 relief: ivory; visible image 9.5 x 5.5 cm.
      Two women, one holding a basket, the other a pitcher, in an oval surrounded by foliage and flowers.
  - Portraits of Don Jose Joaquin Estudillo, his daughter, and his granddaughter, ca. 1847-ca. 1880; BANC PIC 1963.032--FR; 2 paintings, 1 painted photographic print: oil, color; various sizes
    - [Señor Don Jose Joaquin Estudillo], [ca. 1840]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1963.032:01--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 74.3 x 61.8 cm.
      Half length seated portrait with sitter's hand across his chest. Estudillo was Comisionado of Mission Dolores (San Francisco de Asis Mission) from 1834 to 1835 and Alcade of San Francisco in 1836. In 1842 he was granted Rancho San Leandro.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Estudillo family -- Portraits; Estudillo, Jose Joaquin, -- 1798-1852 -- Portraits
    - [Maria de Jesus Estudillo Davis], [ca. 1847]; Barbieri, Leonardo; BANC PIC 1963.032:02--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 80.5 x 65.5 cm.
      Half length seated portrait of sitter wearing lace trimmed dress and gold embroidered gloves. Wearing gold and silver choker, rings, and holding a fan. Born January 5, 1829 Maria de Jesus Telesfora de los Santos Reyes Estudillo, daughter of Jose Joaquin Estudillo, married William Heath Davis in November of 1847 at Mission Dolores, San Francisco (1831 pioneer author of "60 Years in California") and was the mother of Anita Davis. It is possible that this was a marriage portrait.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Estudillo family -- Portraits; Davis, Maria de Jesus Estudillo, -- 1829-1906 -- Portraits
    - [Anita Davis (Mrs. Edwin Clough)], 1870; Fensfeld, J.; BANC PIC 1963.032:03--FR; 1 photograph: retouched with oil; visible oval image 38.5 x 32 cm. Painted signature (LR): J. Fensfeld 1870.
      Bust length portrait of young woman wearing black choker, earrings, lace collar, and brightly colored wrap. She was the daughter of Maria de Jesus Estudillo Davis and granddaughter of Jose Joaquin Estudillo.
      Portraits; Clough, Anita Davis, -- 1849-1919 -- Portraits
  - Items from: Pictorial material from the Eugen Neuhaus papers, ca. 1900-ca. 1930; BANC PIC 1965.033--FR
    - [View of a Lake], [ca. 1900-ca. 1930]; Neuhaus, Eugen; BANC PIC 1965.033:01--FR; 1 painting on academy panel: oil; 22.3 x 38 cm. Painted signature (LR): Eugen Neuhaus. Stamp of artist on verso.
    - [Rooftops in Kassel, Germany], 1896; Neuhaus, Eugen; BANC PIC 1965.033:02--AX; 1 painting on paper: gouache; visible image 12.8 x 27.7 cm. Handwritten (label on verso): Painted by / [stamp] Eugen Neuhaus/ University of California / at Berkeley [end stamp] / at Kassel, Germany / in the year 1896. / (one of my earliest attempts at painting.) / Eugen Neuhaus / Berkeley. California / Oct. 10th 1938.
      View looking over rooftops of city.
      Paintings; Cityscapes -- Germany
    - Lake [Merced?], [ca. 1900-ca. 1930]; Neuhaus, Eugen; BANC PIC 1965.033:03--FR; 1 painting on artist board: oil; visible image 24.2 x 31.9 cm. Painted signature (LL): Eugen Neuhaus. Handwritten (verso): Lake [Merced?] / Eugen Neuhaus. Stamped (verso): Schussler Bros. / Artist Materials / Picture, Mirrors and Frames / 285 Geary Street / San Francisco.
      View of small lake surrounded by trees and bushes.
    - [California Bungalow], [ca. 1900-ca. 1930]; Neuhaus, Eugen; BANC PIC 1965.033:04--FR; 1 painting on board wood composition: oil; 25.5 x 35.6 cm. Painted signature (LL): Eugen Neuhaus.
      Front porch of small house with garden in front.
  - Items from: Items from the Pony Express Museum, ca. 1850-ca. 1939; BANC PIC 1967.015
    - [Mission Dolores, San Francisco], [ca. 1875]; Lee, Joseph; BANC PIC 1967.015:01--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 27 x 44.8 cm. Painted signature (LL): Joseph Lee. Stamp (verso): Snow and Roos, Depot of Group and Co., Importer and manufacturers of [?]. Exhibition lender note (UL).
      View of western façade of San Francisco de Asis Mission church and buildings seen from northwest. Women and children, a horse and cart, a dog, and chickens in front. Cemetary visible at left.
      Oil paintings; Landscapes (Representations) -- California -- San Francisco
    - [Mission Dolores], 1910; Podchernikoff, Alexis Matthews; BANC PIC 1967.015:10--FR; 1 painting: oil; 46 x 56.2 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): A. M. Podchernikoff / 1910. On stretcher (verso UL): Podchernikoff, Alexis Mathew 1886-1933. Museum label (verso UL).
      View of western façade of San Francisco de Asis Mission (San Francisco, Calif.) in moonlight.
      Oil paintings; Spanish mission buildings -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works; San Francisco de Asis Mission (San Francisco, Calif.) -- Pictorial works
    - San Francisco ca. 1875, Narjot, Ernest; BANC PIC 1967.015:11--FR; 1 photograph; visible image 52.3 x 100 cm. Handwritten (verso LR): E. Narjot - San Francisco ca. 1875 / photo of orig. painting destroyed / in fire - S.F. 1906 / This is the only known print / extant. [...]. Additional provenance information on verso..
      View overlooking San Francisco (in moon light?) from base of Telegraph Hill; cows and livestock near small house in foreground, harbor in distance.
      San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works
    - [Portrait of George Sterling], [not after 1926]; Josaphare, Lionel; BANC PIC 1967.015:12--FR; 1 painting on board: oil; visible image 34.5 x 26.7 cm. Painted signature (LR): L. Josaphare. Handwritten (verso): George Sterling. Also on verso two stamps from the Pony Express Museum.
      Bust length profile of Bohemian poet.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Poets, American -- 20th century -- Portraits; Sterling, George, -- 1869-1926 -- Portraits
    - Lotta's Favorite Songs, [18--?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1967.015:13--FR; 1 photograph; visible image 27.5 x 27.8 cm. Label (verso, UL): The Pony Express Museum, "From Missouri to California - 1860-61" P.O. Box 326 Sonora, California. Stamp (verso): Pony Express Museum.
      Music sheet cover with bust portrait of Lotta [Crabtree].
    - [William Randolph Hearst], [ca. 1900]; Sylvia, Jos. H.; BANC PIC 1967.015:14--FR; 1 painting: oil; 49 x 38.2 cm. Painted signature (LL): Jos. H. Sylvia; verso (UL): Wm. R. Hearst. Museum label on verso.
      Oil paintings; Portraits; Hearst, William Randolph, -- 1863-1951 -- Portraits
  - Items from: Gerald Cassidy pictorial collection, ca. 1900-ca. 1934; BANC PIC 1967.028
    - [Superstition Mountains, Arizona], 1930; Cassidy, Gerald; BANC PIC 1967.028:01--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 54 x 69.5 cm. Painted signature and artist's mark (LL): Gerald [sun symbol] Cassidy. Label (verso): Superstition Mountain, Arizona / by Gerald Cassidy / Santa Fe, New Mexico / 1930. Auction information also on verso.
      View of mountains with horses and cacti in foreground.
      Oil paintings; Landscapes; Arizona -- Pictorial works
    - After the Storm., 1915; Cassidy, Gerald; BANC PIC 1967.028:02--FR; 1 painting: oil; 45.6 x 61.1 cm. Signature (LR): Gerald Cassidy. Handwritten title and date (verso of canvas): After the Storm / 1915 / [G?] - 110.
      Coastal seascape showing surf on the rocks in foreground and stormy skies in the distance.
      Oil paintings; Seascapes
    - Among the Cedars [Goats in New Mexico Landscape], [ca. 1923]; Cassidy, Gerald; BANC PIC 1967.028:03--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 85.7 x 80.9 cm. Title from verso. Painted signature (LR): Gerald [sun symbol] Cassidy. Label (verso LR): 4-122- / Among the Cedars / by Gerald Cassidy / Victor Claessens / Waereghem / Belguige / Made in Belgium. Acquisition information on verso stretcher.
      Two goats among the brush in a wooded desert landscape.
    - [Subovski - Interpretive Dancer: Vanity], [1918]; Cassidy, Gerald; BANC PIC 1967.028:04--FR; 1 painting on canvas oil; visible image 136.5 x 91 cm. Painted signature and artist's mark (UR): Gerald [sun symbol] Cassidy. Label (verso of stretcher): Subovski - / Interpretive Dancer / Grad. at Hippodrome - N.Y.City / Summer 1918. Frame label from Taos N. M.
      Full length portrait of woman posing in peacock feathered costume and headdress. Apparently Subovski was a "vanity" dancer at the Hippodrome. This piece is representative of Cassidy's commercial work in theatrical posters.
  - Items from: Miscellaneous pictorial collections from the Sierra Club collection, BANC PIC 1971.073
    - Sierra Juniper, [ca. 1938]; Curtis, Leland; BANC PIC 1971.073:01--FR; 1 painting on paper: gouache and pencil; visible image 14.5 x 17.5 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leland Curtis. Handwritten title (LL on mat). Provenance and acquisition information on verso.
      Tree in open landscape; Sierra Nevada mountains in distance.
      Landscapes (Representations) -- California; Wilderness areas -- California; Sierra Nevada (Calif. and Nev.) -- Pictorial works; Gouaches
    - Desert Road in Nevada, [1935?]; Curtis, Leland; BANC PIC 1971.073:02--FR; 1 painting on paper: gouache; visible image 14.5 x 17.2 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leland Curtis. Handwritten title (LL on mat). Handwritten (on verso): painted about 1935? / bought 1938. Ownership and acquisition information on verso.
      Broad vista across Nevada desert with mountains in distance.
      Gouaches; Landscapes (Representations) -- Nevada
    - Canyon of the Kern, July 1936; Curtis, Leland; BANC PIC 1971.073:03--FR; 1 painting on paper: gouache and pencil; visible image 14.5 x 17.5 cm. Handwritten signature (LL): Leland Curtis. Handwritten title (LL on mat). Handwritten date (UC verso): July 1936.
      View overlooking broad valley surrounded by high mountains on either side with the Kern River running down center.
    - Forest Near Rush Creek [Calif.], 1938; Curtis, Leland; BANC PIC 1971.073:04--FR; 1 painting on paper: gouache and pencil; visible image 14.7 x 17 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leland Curtis. Handwritten title (LL on mat). Handwritten date (verso). Provenance and acquisition information on verso.
      Landscapes (Representations) -- California; Wilderness areas -- California; Pencil works; Gouaches
    - Ritter and Banner, 1938; Curtis, Leland; BANC PIC 1971.073:05--FR; 1 painting on paper: gouache and pencil; visible image 14.6 x 17.2 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leland Curtis. Handwritten title (LL on mat). Handwritten date (LC verso): 1938. Provenance and acquisition information (on verso).
      View of twin mountain peaks covered with snow looking across mountain plateau.
      Landscapes (Representations) -- California; Wilderness areas -- California; Sierra Nevada (Calif. and Nev.) -- Pictorial works; Pencil works; Gouaches
    - Across The Upper Basin - Kings River, 1939; Curtis, Leland; BANC PIC 1971.073:06--FR; 1 painting on paper: gouache and pencil; visible image 14.6 x 17.5 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leland Curtis. Handwritten title (LL on mat). Handwritten date (UR verso): 1939.
      Broad view of mountain valley surrounded by peaks.
    - Mt. McGee, 1939; Curtis, Leland; BANC PIC 1971.073:07--FR; 1 painting on paper: gouache and pencil; visible image 14.6 x 17.5 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leland Curtis. Handwritten title (LL on mat). Handwritten date (UR verso): 1939.
      View across deep ravine looking towards mountain peak with Juniper in left foreground.
    - Sierra Vista, [1941]; Curtis, Leland; BANC PIC 1971.073:08--FR; 1 painting on paper: gouache; visible image 14.5 x 17.5 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leland Curtis. Handwritten title (LL). Handwritten (on verso): Leland Curtis original / 1941 North of Tuolumne Meadows.
      View of meadow with Aspen trees with mountains in distance.
      Landscapes (Representations) -- Sierra Nevada (Calif. and Nev.); Gouaches
    - Black Kaweah - Morning, 1942; Curtis, Leland; BANC PIC 1971.073:09--FR; 1 painting on paper: gouache and pencil; visible image 17.1 x 22.2 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leland / Curtis. Handwritten title (LL on mat). Date on verso.
      Lake with trees; mountains in distance.
    - Hamilton Lake, [1936]; Curtis, Leland; BANC PIC 1971.073:10--FR; 1 painting on paper: gouache; visible image 14.4. 17.5 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leland Curtis. Handwritten title (LL on mat). Handwritten (on verso): Hamilton Lake / Leland Curtis / 1666 Elevado St. / Los Angeles / July 1936. Addition ownership and acquisition information on verso.
      View of Lake with mountains in distance.
    - Morning at Rae Lake, [1935?]; Curtis, Leland; BANC PIC 1971.073:11--FR; 1 painting on paper: gouache; visible image 14.6 x 17.8 cm. Handwritten signature (LR): Leland Curtis. Handwritten title (LL on mat). Handwritten (LR): 5.
      Tall red stone mountains above lake.
  - Art from the Lewis Ferbrache collection, ca. 1875-1906; BANC PIC 1972.043--FR; 8 items (oil paintings, watercolor, and lithograph); various sizes
    - Mt. Hood, from Lost Lake, Oregon, Oct. 10, 1884; Stuart, James Everett; BANC PIC 1972.043:01--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 44.2 x 75 cm. Handwritten (on canvas verso): No. 334 -18 x 30 - 300.. / Sketch. / Eve. - Mt. Hood, from Lost Lake, Oregon / J.E. Stuart. / Oct. 10, 1884. Signature (LL): 334 / J.E. Stuart / Oct. 10, 1884 original sketch.
      View across lake of snow covered mountain.
      Oil paintings; Hood, Mount (Or.) -- Pictorial works
    - [Indian Encampment in Yosemite Valley], [between 1874 and 1900]; Yelland, Raymond Dabb; BANC PIC 1972.043:02--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 65.8 x 43 cm. Handwritten (verso, cardboard backing - in modern hand):-Probably Raymond Dabb Yelland / (See State Art Commission Travelling Calif. / Art Exhibition 1969-70- for / similar Yelland Yosemite Indian / scene [-LD].
      Two teepees made of wooden planks and a lean-to shelter with two Indian figures near a campfire before them; El Capitan visible at right.
      Oil paintings; Yosemite National Park (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; California -- Pictorial works; Indians of North America -- California -- Pictorial works
    - [San Francisco after the 1906 Earthquake and Fire], [ca. 1906]; Wores, Theodore; BANC PIC 1972.043:03--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 59.5 x 43.6 cm. Signature (LL): Theodore Wores.
      Broad view overlooking ruins of city, possibly from Nob Hill residence, with remnants of formal garden in foreground. Damaged cupola of City Hall visible in distance.
      Oil paintings; Cities and towns; San Francisco (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Earthquake and Fire -- 1906; Earthquakes -- California -- San Francisco -- Pictorial works
    - The Mammoth Trees of California, [18--]; Stielman, G.K.; BANC PIC 1972.043:04--FR; 1 print: woodcut, color; visible dome top image 48.7 x 61.5 cm. Printed (LL): G. K. Stielman, engraver, 4th & Walnut, [Cin.]; (LR): Times Steam Job Color Press Pr.[...]. Printed title (LC).
      View of grove showing hotel, visitors, and the main sights of interest of the giant sequoia.
      Giant sequoia -- California -- Pictorial works; Woodcuts -- Color
    - [Forest and lake scene], [18--?]; Yard, Sydney; BANC PIC 1972.043:05--FR; 1 painting on paper: watercolor; visible image 34. 5 x 24.3 cm. Painted signature (LR): Sydney. J. Yard. Possible auction information on verso.
      Watercolors; Landscapes
    - [Indian child in a forest], [18--?]; Hudson, Grace Carpenter; BANC PIC 1972.043:06--FR; 1 painting on canvas mounted on panel: oil; visible image 20.5 x 26.5 cm. Painted signature (LL): G. Hudson. Handwritten (verso): Hudson, Grace / Indian child in forest.
      Girl seated in dark tangled forest.
      Oil paintings; Indians of North America -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works
    - [Mt. Shasta, California]: [14,440 feet high], 1886; Sulton, F.; BANC PIC 1972.043:07--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 50.2 x 90.9 cm. Painted signature and date (LR): F. Sulton. / 86. Handwritten (verso on stretcher): Mt. Shasta California. 14,440 feet high. Manufacturers mark (on frame): S. C. M. Co.
      Distant view of the mountain with an Indian encampment in the foreground.
      Oil paintings; Mount Shasta (Calif.) -- Pictorial works; Indians of North America -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works
    - [Seascape], [18--]; Espoy, Angel; BANC PIC 1972.043:08--FR; 1 painting: oil; visible image 26.8 x 83 cm. Painted signature (LR): A. Espoy. Handwritten (verso of frame): Angel Espoy - California artist / painted beach scenes, mission scenes / -exhibited with his friend Manuel Valencia.
      View of waves crashing on beach.
  - Series of paintings of a scout and his adventures, 18--?; BANC PIC 1972.044--FR; 5 paintings: oil;
    - [The Scout], [18--?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1972.044:01--FR; 1 painting: oil; 43.5 x 73.8 cm.
      A frontiersman, on horseback and carrying a rifle, looks over his shoulder toward an encampment. Apparently after a series by Alexander Edouart.
    - [The Chase], [18--?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1972.044:02--FR; 1 painting: oil; 43.4 x 73.8 cm.
      A frontiersman on horseback firing a hand gun at group of Spaniards(?), pursuing him on horseback. Apparently after a series by Alexander Edouart.
    - [Black Horse Rider], [18--?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1972.044:03--FR; 1 painting: oil; 43.2 x 66.8 cm.
      A frontiersman fleeing on horseback pursued by an Indian(?) on a black horse followed by large group on horseback. Apparently after a series by Alexander Edouart.
    - [The Death], [18--?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1972.044:04--FR; 1 painting: oil; 43.2 x 74 cm.
      A frontiersman on horseback, firing a rifle over his shoulder and hitting a Spaniard(?) on horseback. Apparently after a series by Alexander Edouart.
    - [Return to Camp], [18--?]; Unknown; BANC PIC 1972.044:05--FR; 1 painting: oil; 43.3 x 73.9 cm.
      A frontiersman on horseback with a rifle over his shoulder, returning to a military(?) encampment, (cannon and American flag visible). Apparently after a series by Alexander Edouart.
  - Portraits of a man and a woman, 1852; BANC PIC 1982.101:01-02--FR; 2 drawings on paper: charcoal; visible image 36 x 27 cm